#### **TIMOTHY MADEGWA**

Tel: 0724245620

Email: timothymadegwa@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/timothymadegwa/

Online Portfolio: <a href="https://timothymadegwa.github.io/MyPortfolio/index.html">https://timothymadegwa.github.io/MyPortfolio/index.html</a>

## **PERSONAL STATEMENT**

Timothy is interested in working with companies with customer data to improve on their customer experience by harnessing the power of Data Analytics and Machine Learning. He perused a Bachelor of Science in Mathematics and Computer Science, gaining knowledge in computer programming, statistical analysis, mathematical modelling, data visualizations, enabling him to analyze and get insights from data. He created an Application called Kopapap that gives instant credit scores to borrowers and reduces the amount of risk to the lender. This application reduces on the amount of time it takes to go through the loan screening process hence making it easier to acquire a small loan.

#### **RELEVANT SKILLS**

- Machine learning
- Python Programming
- Data science
- Enterprise Risk Management
- Financial Risk Management
- Sci-Kit Learn (Ensemble methods, Linear Regression, Decision Trees)
- Pandas
- NumPy
- Matplotlib
- Microsoft Office
- Statistical Data Analysis
- Power BI

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# JANUARY 2020 – CURRENT / CO-FOUNDER AND CEO / AQILA SOFTWARE LIMITED <u>ACCOMPLISHMENTS</u>

- Developed Kopapap, a machine learning web-based application the gives instant credit scoring
- Formed a partnership with Finastra (3<sup>rd</sup> largest Financial services company in the world)
- Developed the Business Plan for Aqila focusing leveraging machine learning in fintech, medicine and education.
- Conducted hour of code sessions to less fortunate children in partnership with Finastra.

# JANUARY 2020 – CURRENT / RISK CONSULTANT / PINEHILL CONSULTING ACCOMPLISHMENTS

• Developed a business plan for the Risk department.

- Developed training material and conducted training on Investments.
- Conducted Risk Assessments on PineHill clients and incorporated risk-based decision making in their Strategic plans.

# APRIL 2018 – DECEMBER 2019 / CONSULTANT / PEOPLE CENTRIC MANAGEMENT COMPANY LIMITED

#### **ACCOMPLISHMENTS**

- Developed content for the statistics classes.
- Came up with practical work to apply statistics learnt.
- Developed python content aimed at demonstrating the use of python in Data Analysis

# SEPTEMBER 2018 – FEBRUARY 2019 / RISK ANALYST / CENTUM BUSINESS SOLUTIONS ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Created a Scoring system to evaluate the level of compliance to the procurement procedures of Centum PLC. This helped to quantify the level of risk.
- Contributed to the development of the Risk tracking system by emphasizing the need to breakdown the data collection process. This helped to break down the risk when analysis is done.
- Conducted independent risk reviews of existing and new products.
- Prepared the quarterly compliance report highlighting the level of compliance of Centum and its subsidiaries.
- Prepared the quarterly Board risk report for Nabo Capital (Centum Subsidiary).
- Prepared the weekly bank concentration report which helped in monitoring the bank concentration levels of Nabo Capital (Centum subsidiary).

#### **EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND**

September 2014-November 2017 / Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology Bachelor of Science in Mathematics and Computer Science – Second Class Upper

### January 2012-December 2013 / London College of St. Lawrence

Uganda Advanced Certificate of Education (U.A.C.E) – 18 points

#### January 2008-December 2011 / London College of St. Lawrence

Uganda Certificate of Education (U.C.E) - 11 Aggregates

#### ADDITIONAL TRAINING AND CERTIFICATIONS

# April 2019 – December 2019/ Machine Learning Resident / IcodeAl

- Underwent training in Python, Machine Learning, Deep Learning and Data Science
- Conducted training sessions on Machine Learning, Deep Learning and Data Science

## April 2019 / DataCamp

- Data Scientist with Python (26 courses)
- Fraud Detection using Python

# 2015 / Peer Leaders / Jhpiego (An affiliate of John Hopkins University)

Peer Leaders, Reproductive health & Life Planning

#### **INTERESTS**

<u>Chess</u>: This helps to Timothy to plan ahead and analyze different situations and take the best alternative.

# **REFEREES**

Ms. Lilian Kahara,

Two Rivers Development Limited

Real Estate Analyst

TEL: 0711667355

Mr. ERIC ONDENYI

Data Scientist

InstaDeep Limited

TEL: 0716137077